A Guide to the Randolph-Meikleham Family Papers, 1792-1882
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Miscellaneous Items, n.d., 10 items. (Box-folder 1:137)
  Fragment of note to Septimia Randolph Meikleham concerning Septimia's possible heartbreak; fragment of hymn "glory to God the holy angels cry;" Unidentified envelope; Unidentified heraldic crest hand drawn and colored; Unidentified fragments and address leaf from W. E. Robinson; Unidentified blank stationary; Fragment of unidentified letter concerning her garden, and with an extended discussion of a slave, Nancy.
- Poetry sent to Septimia Randolph Meikleham, n.d., 23 items. (Box-folder 1:138)
  "And if musick touch thee" "Goldy to Helen" Music "Todos canton la cachucha" "buona notte. Oh! Cara hina" "Oh pescator del onda fedalin" Music "Love not, love not!" "Whas ha ye been al the day" with the following on the verso: "Resolved that this meeting being decidely opposed to the constitutionality of the U.S. Bank, and, of course, its recharter, are also opposed to the restoration of the public deposits." "The numeroue beaux and belles" "A Picture" "She was a fair young girl" "where shall we make her grave?" "How swat at close of silent Eve" "Heard you not a prayer from the East?" "Many a year is in its grave" "By day or night in weal or woe" "Sweet as springtime flowers!" "This world may seem a trifle" "My gondola's waiting below love" "La Feresina" "The moon beams are glowing on dew drops and flower" "Wenn die schwal ben" "The storm beats loud against my window pane" "Oh take her, but be faithful still" "Wha's at the window? Wha? Oh wha?" "Alas, alas, thy fragile flower" "now winter reigns in his own reigns in his own northern clime," dated 1828 January 6 "Friend after friend departs," dated 1829 May 3 "Though bright thy morn of life may seem," dated 1829 July 25 "Too harsh, too sharp, too loud for love," dated 1832 July 30 "Sweet Florida," dated 1836 February 27 "When the silken bands that fettered our youth," dated 1836 May 1 "Lady! Amid the festive throng," dated 1837 May 28; a second copy dated 1837 May night.